American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIj. 1898-1984 APS.Archives.IIj APS.Archives.IIj
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, June 1, 1898; 8x5; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns Fraley and Lesley portraits. Refers to A.H. Smyth, H.L. Carson, W.A. Ingham.
  - Letter to Fred[eric]k Prime, June 1, 1898; 9x5-1/2; Williams, Edward Higginson, 1849-1933
    Bethlehem, Pa., A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks about separates of his paper on Kansan drift in Pennsylvania. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 37, pp. 84-87.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 2, 1898; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Kaiserlich Deutsches Archäologisches Institut
    Berlin, L.S.: [Alexander] Conze 1p. In German Declines to exchange.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 3, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Cushing, Harry Alonzo, 1870-1955
    [New York], A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for assistance. A.P.S. will receive Columbia publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 3, 1898; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends copy of Edmunds' letter to him, May 18, 1898, about revision of A.P.S. laws. For copy, see Edmunds to Frazer, May 18, 1898.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 3, 1898; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Cannot find Edmunds' letter to him or the book of engrossed minutes.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, June 3, 1898; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L.S. 2p. Concerns duties of Secretaries.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 3, 1898; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Journal des économistes
    Paris, L. on postal card 1p. and add. In French. Declines to exchange publications.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, June 4, 1898; 10x8; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
    Washington, D.C., Typed L.S. 1p. Sending Vols. 2-6 of the Official Records of the Union and Confederate Navies, for the A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 6, 1898; 9x6; Culin, Stewart, 1858-1929
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns F.A. Davis & Co.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 6, 1898; 5x8; Sachse, Julius Friedrich, 1842-1919
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns plates for S.N. Rhoads' paper on beavers. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol. 19, pp. 417-439.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 6, 1898; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Kaiserl. Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien
    Vienna, L.S.: [Alfons] Huber 2p., end. In German Lists Proceedings missing from its file.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 7, 1898; 11x8; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns procedure for calling committee meetings.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, June 8, 1898; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Flexner, Bernard, 1865-1945
    Louisville, Ky., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hayes [sic], June 8, 1898; 9-1/2x6; Ingham, William A. (William Armstrong), 1827-1913
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends MS. of his remarks made at reception for J.P. Lesley's portrait.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 9, 1898; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Has called meeting of Secretaries. Refers to A.P.S. laws.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 9, 1898; 9x8; MacCalla & co., inc.
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Enc. wanting Explains defective copies of Proceedings, #156. Returns sample copy.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 11, 1898; 8-3/4x5-3/4; Deutsche Morgenländische Gesellschaft
    Halle, A.L.S.: Praetorius 2p. and end. In German Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 11, 1898; 8x5; Historical Society of Pennsylvania
    Phila., A.L.S.: Gregory B[arnard] Keen 2p. Offers publications: Catalogue of C. Tower Collection, Hildeburn's Inscriptions in St. Peter's Churchyard.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, June 11, 1898; 8-1/2 x8-1/4; Whelan, Ralph
    Minneapolis, Minn., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Mutilated Inquires about Phillips prize. On verso is draft of reply by W.V. McKean.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 12, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; See, T. J. J. (Thomas Jefferson Jackson), b. 1866
    Flagstaff, Ariz., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for separates of paper on stellar systems. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol. 19, pp. 221-235.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 13, 1898; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Lancaster County Historical Society (Pa.)
    Lanc[aster], Pa., A.L.S.: S.M. Sener, on postal card 1p. and add. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, June 13, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Scott, William Berryman, 1858-1947
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Change of address.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, June 14, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Media, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns Hewett's paper.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 14, 1898; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Deutsche Morgenländische Gesellschaft
    Halle, A.L.S.: Praetorius, on postal card 1p. and add. In German Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, June 15, June 17, 1898; 10x8; Institution of Mechanical Engineers (Great Britain)
    London, Typed L.S.: Edgar Worthington 2 items 2p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hayes [sic], June 17, 1898; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Ingham, William A. (William Armstrong), 1827-1913
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends proof of his remarks on Lesley portrait.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, June 17, 1898; 9x6; Prime, Frederick, 1846-1915
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. His name to be added to new edition of A.P.S. Charter.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, June 18, 1898; 10x8; United States. Superintendent of Documents
    Washington, D.C., T.L.S. with stamp: L. C. Ferrell 1p. Concerns copy of Records of Union and Confederate Navies for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 19, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Koninklijk Instituut voor de Taal-, Land- en Volkenkunde van Nederlandsch-Indië
    's-Gravenhage, A.L.S.:[E. B.] Kielstra 1p., end. In Dutch Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, June 21, 1898; 10x8; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
    Washington, D.C., Typed L. with MS. correction S. 1p. Sending publication for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, June 21, 1898; 10x8; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
    Washington, D.C., Typed L.S. 1p. Will try to obtain requested publications for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 21, 1898; 10-1/2x8; United States. Superintendent of Documents
    Washington, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. Forwarding requested documents to A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 22, 1898; 4-1/2x7; Claypole, E. W. (Edward Waller), 1835-1901
    Akron, O., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends subscription and changes address.
  - Letter to Boies Penrose, June 22, 1898; 10x8; United States. Dept. of State
    Washington, Typed L.S.: William R[ufus] Day 1p. Has sent publications to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 23, July 15, Nov. 28, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2, 3-1/2x5-1/2; Los Angeles Public Library
    Los Angeles, Cal., L. 3 items, one of them on postal card 3p. and add. Purchase of publications.
  - Letter to [Ella M.] Morrison [sic], June 24, 1898; 9-1/2x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end., and end. Concerns series in library. Refers to Royal Society of London, Academy of natural sciences of Philadelphia.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hay [sic], June 24, 1898; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Lebanon County Historical Society (Lebanon County, Pa.)
    Heilman Dale, Pa., A.L.S.: S. P. Heilman, Secretary 1p. Exchange of publications. Written on verso of printed announcement.
  - Letter to Boies Penrose, June 24, 1898; 10x8; United States. Dept. of State
    Washington [D.C.] Typed L.S.: William R[ufus] Day 1p., end. Sending copy of president's proclamation to A.P.S. library, as requested.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], June 26, 1898; 8-3/4x5-3/4; Historische vierteljahrschrift
    Leipzig, A.L.S.: Kätzschke 1p. In German Declines to exchange publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 27, 1898; 9x6; MacCalla & co., inc.
    Phila., L.S.: W[illia]m A. Pickell 1p., end.: Referred to Mr. Stockhausen to explain. I.M. Hays Concerns shortage of plates for H. Allen's paper.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, June 27, 1898; 9x6; Scott, William Berryman, 1858-1947
    Princeton [N.J.] A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends a cut for a paper.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, June 27, 1898; 6-1/2x8; Sulter, H. W.
    Savannah, Ga., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 29, 1898; 9x6; Stockhausen, P.C., co.
    Phila., L. 1p. Concerns shortage of plates for Harrison Allen's paper.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June, 1898; 11-1/4x8-1/4; Gesellschaft zur Beförderung der Gesammten Naturwissenschaften zu Marburg
    Marburg, Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: [Otto von] Heusinger 1p. Enc. wanting In German Sends publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June, 1898; 6-3/4x5-1/4; Miller, G. A. (George Abram), 1863-1951
    Ithaca, N.Y., A.L.S. 2p. Enc. wanting Sends paper on Quaternion groups. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 37, pp. 312-319.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, July 1, 1898; 11x8-1/2; MacCalla & co., inc.
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Concerns plate for paper by W.C. Day. For Printed Paper, see: APS Proceedings. vol. 37, pp. 171-174.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 2, 1898; 10x8; Hewett, Waterman Thomas, 1846-1921
    [lthaca, N.Y.], A.L.S. 1p. Asks to withdraw paper on Goethe's text since it has not been published after six months.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis Hays], July 4, 1898; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Paris. École d'anthropologie
    Paris, A.L.S.: J. Fleschelle 1p., end. In French Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 4, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Sampson, Alden, 1853-1925
    Haverford, [Pa.], A.L.S. 3p. Corrects name in minutes.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, July 7, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Century Company
    New York, Typed L.S.: A[lexander] W[ilson] Drake 1p. Article on Franklin by P.L. Ford. Sachse to photograph Franklin items for illustrations if permitted by A.P.S.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis Hays], July 7, 1898; 11x8-1/2; United States. War Records Office
    Washington, Typed L. 1p., end. Concerns copy of War Records Atlas for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, July 8, 1898; 9x8; MacCalla & co., inc.
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Concerns P.C. Stockhausen and the plates for Hays' paper on APS copy of Declaration of Independence. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol 37, pp. 88-107.
  - Letter to [P.C.] Stockhausen, July 8, 1898; 9x6; MacCalla and co., inc.
    Phila., L. 2p., end. Mutilated Need plates for Harrison Allen's paper.
  - Letter to [Samuel Phillip] Sadtler, July 8, 1898; 10x8; Trimble, Henry, 1853-1898
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Recommends book purchases for Library.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, July 9, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Century Company
    New York, Typed L.S.: A[lexander] W[ilson] Drake 1p. Asks for additional photographs of Franklin items to be made by Sachse for P.L. Ford article.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, July 9, 1898; 10x8; Hewett, Waterman Thomas, 1846-1921
    Ithaca, N.Y., A.L.S.1p. Asks for return of MS. on Goethe's text.
  - Letter to J.B. Lippincott co., Phila., July 11, 1898; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Charles E. Lauriat Co.
    Boston, L. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Asks about paper by F.H. Cushing on Florida expedition.
  - Letter to H[enry] C[hapman] Mercer, July 11, 1898; 9x8; MacCalla and co., inc.
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Concerns Stockhausen's bill for plates. Refers to I.M. Hays.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, July 12, 1898; 9x8, 3-1/2x5-1/2; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Enc. of postal card Forwards inquiry from C.E. Lauriat co. to Lippincott about Cushing's paper on Florida expedition.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, July 13, 1898; 4x5; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    Doylestown, Pa., A.L. on card S. 2p. Enc. wanting Sends letter from MacCalla explaining Stockhausen's bill. Concerns his paper (on Fraktur?) For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 424-433. For enclosure, see MacCalla & co. to H.C. Mercer July 11, 1898.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, July 14, 1898; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Rhoads, Samuel N. (Samuel Nicholson), b. 1862
    [Summit, Pa.] A.L. on postal card S. 1p. and add. Send proofs of paper on beavers to him at Summit. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol. 19, pp. 417-439.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 15, 1898; 8x8; Billups, A. C.
    Lawrenceburg, Md., A.L.S. 1p., end. Orders APS publications on mollusks.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, July 15, 1898; 9-1/2x6; Elliot, A. G., & Co.
    Phila., L. 1p. Encs. wanting Sends samples of blotting paper.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, July 17, 1898; 10x8; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
    Washington, D.C., Typed L.S. 1p. Sending publications for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 19, 1898; 7-1/2x8; Houghton, Mifflin and Company
    Cambridge, Mass., L. 1p. Concerns seal of A.P.S.
  - Letter to [Ella M] Morison, July 19, 1898; 9x6; MacCalla and co., inc.
    Phila., L.S.: W[illiam] A Pickell 1p. Sending advance copies of proceedings and proofs of mailing List.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 19, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Pennsylvania. Secretary of the Commonwealth
    Harrisburg [Pa.] Typed L. 1p. Sends copy of Pennsylvania Archives for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, July 19, 1898; 10x8; United States. War Dept.
    Washington [D.C.] Typed L.S.: G[eorge] D[eRue] Meiklejohn 1p. Sending copies of documents for A.P.S. library as requested by B. Penrose.
  - Letter to [Ella M] Morison, July 21, 1898; 8x5; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns Fraley and Lesley portraits. Refers to Mrs. Lesley, I.M. Hays.
  - Letter to [Ella M] Morison, July 22, 1898; 9x6; MacCalla and co., inc.
    Phila., L.S.: W[illia]m A Pickell 2p. Encs. wanting Sends proofs. Concerns mailing of Proceedings. Refers to W.A. Ingham, J.G. Rosengarten, I.M.Hays.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, July 22, 1898; 8x5; Historical Society of Pennsylvania
    Phila., L. 1p. Concerns the Pennsylvania Archives.
  - Letter to [Ella M] Morison, July 22, 1898; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    [Phila.] A.L. on postal card S. 1p., end., and add. Send reprints of Fraley portrait address to H.L. Carson. Mentions W.A. Ingham, I.M. Hays.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 23, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Branner, John Casper, 1850-1922
    Stanford University, Cal., A.L.S. 1p. Asks to use illustrations from papers by Drake and Ashley. For printed papers, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36,pp. 217-318, 326-419.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, July 23, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    A.L.S. 1p., end. Has not received Proceedings, No. 156.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 25, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Pennsylvania. Secretary of the Commonwealth
    Harrisburg [Pa.] Typed L. 1p. Sending copy of Pennsylvania Archives, 3d Series for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, July 25, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Pettit, Henry, 1842-1921
    Overbrook [Pa.] A.L.S. 2p. Requests copy of Hays' paper on A.P.S. copy of Declaration of Independence. Refers to Roberdeau Buchanan. For printed paper, see: A.P.S. Proceedings, vol. 36, pp.88-107.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, July 26, 1898; 9x8; MacCalla & co., inc.
    Phila., Typed L. with MS. corrections, S.: W[illia]m A Pickell 2p. Concerns papers by W.B. Scott and S.N. Rhoads. For printed papers, see: APS Transactions, n.s., Vol.19, pp. 273-324, 325-415, 417-439.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 26, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, D.C., Typed L.S.: Richard Rathbun 1p., end. Enc. Sends list of A.P.S. exchanges lost in sinking of steamship "La Bourgogne."
  - letter to the American philosophical society, July 28, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Geological Survey of India
    Calcutta, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. Concerns publication of its Records.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 28, 1898; 8-1/2x7; Geological Survey of India
    Calcutta, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. Its Records will be incorporated into its Memoirs.
  - Letter to J. Minis Hayes [sic, Isaac Minis Hays], July 29, 1898; 9-1/2x6-1/2; Buchanan, Roberdeau, 1839-1916
    Buena Vista Spring, Pa., A.L.S. 4p. Thanks for paper on APS copy of Declaration of Independence. Sends copy of his McKean genealogy for library. Refers to Thomas McKean, William Shippen, Samuel Blair, George Buchanan, Henry Pettit. For printed paper. see: APS Proceedings, vol. 37, pp. 88-107.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 31, 1898; 8x5-1/2; Mathews, R. H. (Robert Hamilton), 1841-1918
    Parramatta, New South Wales, A.L.S. 1p., end. Thanks for separates of his paper on division of Australian tribes. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 37, pp. 151-154.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hayes [sic], Aug. 1, 1898; 8x5-1/2; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns William Pepper's death.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Aug. 2, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Charles E. Lauriat Co.
    Boston, L. 1p., end. Orders copy of Cushing's paper.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 2, 1898; 8x5; Pepper, George Wharton, 1867-1961
    [Phila.] L.S. 2p. Arrangements for William Pepper's funeral.
  - Letter to C. Hays [sic, Isaac Minis Hays], Aug. 2, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Niagara Falls, N.Y., Typed L.S. 2p. Sudden death of William Pepper. E.G. Acheson and his new method of making graphite.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, August 3, 1898; 11x8-1/2; MacCalla and co., inc.
    Phila., Typed L. with MS. corrections 1p. Concerns Stockhausen's plates for H. Allen's paper. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol. 19, pp. 237-266, 267-272.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, Aug. 3, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
    Washington, D.C., Typed L.S. 1p. Sending copies of presidential proclamations for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Aug. 4, 1898; 9x8; MacCalla & co., inc.
    Phila., Typed L. with MS. corrections 1p. Concerns separata for [Earl?] Douglass.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 5, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Rand, McNally and Company
    New York, L. 1p., end. Asks for information on A.P.S.
  - Letter to F[rederick] Fraley, Aug. 5, 1898; 8x5; Wistar, Isaac J. (Isaac Jones), 1827-1905
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns funeral of W. Pepper.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Aug. 6, 1898; 9x5-3/4; Prime, Frederick, 1846-1915
    Lake Luzerne, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p. Regrets he could not attend W. Pepper's funeral.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 8, 1898; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L.S. 1p. Concerns death of William Pepper.
  - Letter to J. Minnis [sic, Isaac Minis] Hays, Aug. 8, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
    Washington, D.C., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns copies of presidential proclamations for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Aug. 9, 1898; 8x5; Rhoads, Samuel N. (Samuel Nicholson), b. 1862
    Pittsburgh, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Returns proofs of paper on beavers. For printed paper. see; APS Transactions, n.s. vol. 19, pp. 417-439.
  - Letter to J. Minnis [sic, Isaac Minis] Hays, Aug. 10, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Aug. 11, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Franklin Institute (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    Phila., Typed L.S.: Jo[h]n Birkinbine, President 1p. Death of William Pepper.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Aug. 11, 1898; 8x5; Rhoads, Samuel N. (Samuel Nicholson), b. 1862
    Pittsburgh, Pa., A.L.S. 3p. Plates for his paper on beavers are very poor. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol. 19, pp. 417-439.
  - Receipts for admission fee and for contribution, Aug. 11, 1898; 8x6; Ware, Lewis S. (Lewis Sharpe), 1851-1918
    Typed copies 1p., end.: With Mr. H[enry] C[arey] Baird's compliments
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 17, 1898; 3-1/4x5-1/2; Indiana. Dept. of Geology and Natural Resources
    Indianapolis, Ind., Typed L. on postal card 1p. and add. 22d Report is ready.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Aug. 19, 1898; 9x8; MacCalla and co., inc.
    Phila., Typed L. 1p., end.: Will Mr. Stockhausen please explain this to Dr. Hays - and return letter Concerns shortage of Harrison Allen plates.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Aug. 19, 1898; 8x5; Rhoads, Samuel N. (Samuel Nicholson), b. 1862
    Pittsburgh, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. New plates are very good. Returns proof. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol. 19, pp. 417-439.
  - Invoice for publications of the Deutsche morganländische gesellschaft, Aug. 20, 1898; 5-3/4x8-1/2; F. A. Brockhaus (Firm)
    to the A.P.S.: Leipzig, D. 1p. In German.
  - Letter to J[ames] Cheston Morris, Aug. 20, 1898; 11x8; Pennsylvania Museum and School of Industrial Art
    Phila., Typed D.S.: Dalton Dorr 1p. Asks to borrow Marsden's Numismata Orientalia for H.M. Wilder, who is working on India coins. Refers to Numismatic and Antiquarian Society, R.S. Culin.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Aug. 20, 1898; 8x5; Rhoads, Samuel N. (Samuel Nicholson), b. 1862
    Pittsburgh, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. Has sent corrected galleys of paper on beavers. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol. 19, pp. 417-439.
  - Letter to I Minus Hayes [sic, Isaac Minis Hays], Aug. 20, 1898; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Rhoads, Samuel N. (Samuel Nicholson), b. 1862
    Pittsburgh, Pa., L. on postal card 1p. and add. Asks about missing proof of paper on beavers. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol. 19, pp. 417-439.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Aug. 22, 1898; 9x6; MacCalla & co., inc.
    Phila., L. 1p. Concerns separates for S.N. Rhoads.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 23, 1898; 13x8; Great Britain. Treasury
    [London], Typed L.S.: [Sir] Francis Mowatt 1p. Cannot supply copies of the "Challenger Reports."
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Aug. 23, 1898; 9x6; Stockhausen, P.C., co.
    Phila., L. 2p. Enc. wanting. Concerns shortage of Harrison Allen plates. Sends memo received from MacCalla and Co. For enclosure, see MacCalla and co. to [P.C.] Stockhausen, July 8, 1898.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 25, 1898; 9x6; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    A.L.S. 1p. Will read paper on "Linguistic Cartography of the Chaco Region" at next meeting. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, Vol. 37, pp. 178-205.
  - Letter to [James Cheston] Morris, Aug. 25, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Pennsylvania Museum and School of Industrial Art
    Phila., A.L.S.: Dalton Dorr 2p. Refers to H.M. Wilder and his work on A.P.S. numismatic collection, and Mr. Hunersdorff.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Aug. 25, 1898; 8x5; Rhoads, Samuel N. (Samuel Nicholson), b. 1862
    Pittsburgh, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Returns proof of paper on beavers. Refers to Witmer Stone. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol. 19, pp. 417-439.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Aug. 27, 1898; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Media, Pa., Typed L.S. 1p. Has received revised Constitution. Please enter his paper for October.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Aug. 27, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Rhoads, Samuel N. (Samuel Nicholson), b. 1862